In the previous video, I talked
在前面的课程中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
about error analysis and the
我提到了误差分析
importance of having error
以及设定误差度量值的重要性
metrics, that is of having
那就是
a single real number evaluation metric
设定某个实数来评估你的学习算法
for your learning algorithm to tell how well it's doing.
并衡量它的表现
In the context of evaluation
有了算法的评估
and of error metrics, there is
和误差度量值
one important case, where it's
有一件重要的事情要注意
particularly tricky to come
就是使用一个合适的误差度量值
up with an appropriate error metric,
这有时会对于你的学习算法
or evaluation metric, for your learning algorithm.
造成非常微妙的影响
That case is the case
这件重要的事情就是
of what's called skewed classes.
偏斜类（skewed classes）的问题
Let me tell you what that means.
让我告诉你这是什么意思
Consider the problem of cancer
想一想之前的癌症分类问题
classification, where we have
我们拥有
features of medical patients and
内科病人的特征变量
we want to decide whether or not they have cancer.
我们希望知道他们是否患有癌症
So this is like the malignant
因此这就像恶性
versus benign tumor classification
与良性肿瘤的分类问题
example that we had earlier.
我们之前讲过这个
So let's say y equals 1 if the
我们假设 y=1 表示患者患有癌症
patient has cancer and y equals 0
假设 y=0
if they do not.
表示他们没有得癌症
We have trained the progression
我们训练逻辑回归模型
classifier and let's say
假设我们用测试集
we test our classifier on
检验了这个分类模型
a test set and find that we get 1 percent error.
并且发现它只有1%的错误
So, we're making 99% correct diagnosis.
因此我们99%会做出正确诊断
Seems like a really impressive result, right.
看起来是非常不错的结果
We're correct 99% percent of the time.
我们99%的情况都是正确的
But now, let's say we find
但是 假如我们发现
out that only 0.5 percent
在测试集中
of patients in our
只有0.5%的患者
training test sets actually have cancer.
真正得了癌症
So only half a
因此
percent of the patients that
在我们的筛选程序里
come through our screening process have cancer.
只有0.5%的患者患了癌症
In this case, the 1%
因此在这个例子中
error no longer looks so impressive.
1%的错误率就不再显得那么好了
And in particular, here's a piece
举个具体的例子
of code, here's actually a piece
这里有一行代码
of non learning code that takes
不是机器学习代码
this input of features x and it ignores it.
它忽略了输入值X
It just sets y equals 0
它让y总是等于0
and always predicts, you
因此它总是预测
know, nobody has cancer and this
没有人得癌症
algorithm would actually get
那么这个算法实际上只有
0.5 percent error.
0.5%的错误率
So this is even better than
因此这甚至比
the 1% error that we were getting just now
我们之前得到的1%的错误率更好
and this is a non
这是一个
learning algorithm that you know, it is just
非机器学习算法
predicting y equals 0 all the time.
因为它只是预测y总是等于0
So this setting of when
这种情况发生在
the ratio of positive to
正例和负例的比率
negative examples is very close
非常接近于
to one of two extremes, where,
一个极端
in this case, the number of
在这个例子中
positive examples is much,
正样本的数量
much smaller than the number
与负样本的数量相比
of negative examples because y
非常非常少
equals one so rarely, this
因为y=1非常少
is what we call the
我们把这种情况叫做
case of skewed classes.
偏斜类
We just have a lot more
一个类中的样本数
of examples from one class
与另一个类的数据相比
than from the other class.
多很多
And by just predicting y equals
通过总是预测y=0
0 all the time, or maybe
或者
our predicting y equals 1
总是预测y=1
all the time, an algorithm can do pretty well.
算法可能表现非常好
So the problem with using
因此使用分类误差
classification error or classification
或者分类精确度
accuracy as our evaluation metric is the following.
来作为评估度量可能会产生如下问题
Let's say you have one joining
假如说你有一个算法
algorithm that's getting 99.2% accuracy.
它的精确度是99.2%
So, that's a 0.8% error.
因此它只有0.8%的误差
Let's say you
假设
make a change to your algorithm
你对你的算法做出了一点改动
and you now are getting
现在你得到了
99.5% accuracy.
99.5%的精确度
That is 0.5% error.
只有0.5%的误差
So, is this an improvement to the algorithm or not?
这到底是不是算法的一个提升呢
One of the nice things
用某个实数来
about having a single real
作为评估度量值
number evaluation metric is this
的一个好处就是
helps us to quickly decide if
它可以帮助我们迅速决定
we just need a good change to the algorithm or not.
我们是否需要对算法做出一些改进
By going from 99.2% accuracy to 99.5% accuracy.
将精确度从99.2%提高到99.5%
You know, did we just do something
但是我们的改进到底是有用的
useful or did we
还是说
just replace our code with
我们只是把代码替换成了
something that just predicts y equals
例如总是预测y=0
zero more often?
这样的东西
So, if you have very skewed classes
因此如果你有一个偏斜类
it becomes much harder to use
用分类精确度
just classification accuracy, because you
并不能很好地衡量算法
can get very high classification accuracies
因为你可能会获得一个很高的精确度
or very low errors, and
非常低的错误率
it's not always clear if
但是我们并不知道
doing so is really improving
我们是否真的提升了
the quality of your classifier
分类模型的质量
because predicting y equals 0 all the
因为总是预测y=0
time doesn't seem like
并不是一个
a particularly good classifier.
好的分类模型
But just predicting y equals 0 more
但是总是预测y=0
often can bring your error
会将你的误差降低至
down to, you know, maybe as
比如
low as 0.5%.
降低至0.5%
When we're faced with such
当我们遇到
a skewed classes therefore we
这样一个偏斜类时
would want to come up
我们希望有一个
with a different error metric
不同的误差度量值
or a different evaluation metric.
或者不同的评估度量值
One such evaluation metric are
其中一种评估度量值
what's called precision recall.
叫做查准率（precision）和召回率（recall）
Let me explain what that is.
让我来解释一下
Let's say we are evaluating a classifier on the test set.
假设我们正在用测试集来评估一个分类模型
For the examples in the
对于
test set the actual
测试集中的样本
class of that example
每个测试集中的样本
in the test set is going to
都会等于
be either one or zero, right,
0或者1
if there is a binary classification problem.
假设这是一个二分问题
And what our learning algorithm
我们的学习算法
will do is it will, you know,
要做的是
predict some value for the
做出值的预测
class and our learning
并且学习算法
algorithm will predict the value
会为每一个
for each example in my
测试集中的实例
test set and the predicted value
做出预测
will also be either one or zero.
预测值也是等于0或1
So let me draw a two
让我画一个
by two table as follows,
2x2的表格
depending on a full of these entries
基于所有这些值
depending on what was the
基于
actual class and what was the predicted class.
实际的类与预测的类
If we have an
如果
example where the actual class is
有一个样本它实际所属的类是1
one and the predicted class
预测的类也是1
is one then that's called
那么
an example that's a true
我们把这个样本叫做真阳性（true positive）
positive, meaning our algorithm
意思是说我们的学习算法
predicted that it's positive
预测这个值为阳性
and in reality the example is positive.
实际上这个样本也确实是阳性
If our learning algorithm predicted that
如果我们的学习算法
something is negative, class zero,
预测某个值是阴性 等于0
and the actual class is also
实际的类也确实属于0
class zero then that's what's called a true negative.
那么我们把这个叫做真阴性（true negative）
We predicted zero and it actually is zero.
我们预测为0的值实际上也等于0
To find the other two boxes,
还剩另外的两个单元格
if our learning algorithm predicts that
如果我们的学习算法
the class is one but the
预测某个值等于1
actual class is zero, then
但是实际上它等于0
that's called a false positive.
这个叫做假阳性（false positive）
So that means our algorithm for
比如我们的算法
the patient is cancelled out in
预测某些病人患有癌症
reality if the patient does not.
但是事实上他们并没有得癌症
And finally, the last box is a zero, one.
最后 这个单元格是 1和0
That's called a false negative
这个叫做假阴性（false negative）
because our algorithm predicted
因为我们的算法预测值为0
zero, but the actual class was one.
但是实际值是1
And so, we
这样
have this little sort of two by
我们有了一个2x2的表格
two table based on
基于
what was the actual class and what was the predicted class.
实际类与预测类
So here's a different way
这样我们有了一个
of evaluating the performance of
另一种方式来
our algorithm. We're
评估算法的表现
going to compute two numbers.
我们要计算两个数字
The first is called precision -
第一个叫做查准率
and what that says is,
这个意思是
of all the patients where we've
对于所有我们预测
predicted that they have cancer,
他们患有癌症的病人
what fraction of them actually have cancer?
有多大比率的病人是真正患有癌症的
So let me write this down,
让我把这个写下来
the precision of a classifier
一个分类模型的查准率
is the number of true
等于
positives divided by
真阳性除以
the number that we predicted
所有我们预测为阳性
as positive, right?
的数量
So of all the patients that
对于那些病人
we went to those patients and we told them, "We think you have cancer."
我们告诉他们 "你们患有癌症"
Of all those patients, what
对于这些病人而言
fraction of them actually have cancer?
有多大比率是真正患有癌症的
So that's called precision.
这个就叫做查准率
And another way to write this
另一个写法是
would be true positives and
分子是真阳性
then in the denominator is the
分母是
number of predicted positives, and
所有预测阳性的数量
so that would be the
那么这个等于
sum of the, you know, entries
表格第一行的值
in this first row of the table.
的和
So it would be true positives divided by true positives.
也就是真阳性除以真阳性...
I'm going to abbreviate positive
这里我把阳性简写为
as POS and then
POS
plus false positives, again
加上假阳性
abbreviating positive using POS.
这里我还是把阳性简写为POS
So that's called precision, and as you
这个就叫做查准率
can tell high precision would be good.
查准率越高就越好
That means that all the patients
这是说 对于那些病人
that we went to and we said, "You know, we're very sorry.
我们告诉他们 "非常抱歉
We think you have cancer," high precision
我们认为你得了癌症"
means that of that group
高查准率说明
of patients most of them
对于这类病人
we had actually made accurate
我们对预测他们得了癌症
predictions on them and they do have cancer.
有很高的准确率
The second number we're going to compute
另一个数字我们要计算的
is called recall, and what
叫做召回率
recall say is, if all
召回率是
the patients in, let's say,
如果所有的病人
in the test set or the
假设测试集中的病人
cross-validation set, but if
或者交叉验证集中的
all the patients in the data
如果所有这些在数据集中的病人
set that actually have cancer,
确实得了癌症
what fraction of them that
有多大比率
we correctly detect as having cancer.
我们正确预测他们得了癌症
So if all the patients have
如果所有的病人
cancer, how many of them
都患了癌症
did we actually go to them
有多少人我们能够
and you know, correctly told them that we think they need treatment.
正确告诉他们 你需要治疗
So, writing this down,
把这个写下来
recall is defined as the
召回率被定义为
number of positives, the number
真阳性
of true positives,
的数量
meaning the number of people
意思是我们正确预测
that have cancer and that
患有癌症的人
we correctly predicted have cancer
的数量
and we take that and divide
我们用这个来
that by, divide that by
除以
the number of actual positives,
实际阳性
so this is the right
这个值是
number of actual positives of all the people that do have cancer.
所有患有癌症的人的数量
What fraction do we directly
有多大比率
flag and you know, send the treatment.
我们能正确发现癌症 并给予治疗
So, to rewrite this in
把这个以另一种形式
a different form, the denominator would
写下来
be the number of actual
分母是
positives as you know, is the sum
实际阳性的数量
of the entries in this first column over here.
表格第一列值的和
And so writing things out differently,
将这个以不同的形式写下来
this is therefore, the number of
那就是
true positives, divided by
真阳性除以
the number of true positives
真阳性
plus the number of
加上
false negatives.
假阴性
And so once again, having a high recall would be a good thing.
同样地 召回率越高越好
So by computing precision and
通过计算查准率
recall this will usually
和召回率
give us a better sense of
我们能更好的知道
how well our classifier is doing.
分类模型到底好不好
And in particular if we have
具体地说
a learning algorithm that predicts
如果我们有一个算法
y equals zero all
总是预测y=0
the time, if it predicts no
它总是预测
one has cancer, then this
没有人患癌症
classifier will have a
那么这个分类模型
recall equal to zero,
召回率等于0
because there won't be any
因为它不会有
true positives and so that's
真阳性
a quick way for us to
因此我们能会快发现
recognize that, you know, a
这个分类模型
classifier that predicts y equals 0 all the time,
总是预测y=0
just isn't a very good classifier.
它不是一个好的模型
And more generally,
总的来说
even for settings where we
即使我们有一个
have very skewed classes, it's
非常偏斜的类
not possible for an
算法也不能够
algorithm to sort of "cheat"
"欺骗"我们
and somehow get a very
仅仅通过预测
high precision and a
y总是等于0
very high recall by doing
或者y总是等于1
some simple thing like predicting
它没有办法得到
y equals 0 all the time or
高的查准率
predicting y equals 1 all the time.
和高的召回率
And so we're much
因此我们
more sure that a classifier
能够更肯定
of a high precision or high recall
拥有高查准率或者高召回率的模型
actually is a good classifier,
是一个好的分类模型
and this gives us a
这给予了我们一个
more useful evaluation metric that
更好的评估值
is a more direct way to
给予我们一种更直接的方法
actually understand whether, you know, our algorithm may be doing well.
来评估模型的好与坏
So one final note in
最后一件需要记住的事
the definition of precision and
在查准率和召回率的定义中
recall, that we would define
我们定义
precision and recall, usually we
查准率和召回率
use the convention that y is equal to 1, in
我们总是习惯性地用y=1
the presence of the more rare class.
如果这个类出现得非常少
So if we are trying to detect.
因此如果我们试图检测
rare conditions such as cancer,
某种很稀少的情况 比如癌症
hopefully that's a rare condition,
我希望它是个很稀少的情况
precision and recall are
查准率和召回率
defined setting y equals
会被定义为
1, rather than y
y=1
equals 0, to be sort of
而不是y=0
that the presence of that rare
作为某种我们希望检测的
class that we're trying to detect.
出现较少的类
And by using precision and recall,
通过使用查准率和召回率
we find, what happens is
我们发现
that even if we have
即使我们拥有
very skewed classes, it's not
非常偏斜的类
possible for an algorithm to
算法不能够
you know, "cheat" and predict
通过总是预测y=1
y equals 1 all the time,
来"欺骗"我们
or predict y equals 0 all
或者总是预测y=0
the time, and get high precision and recall.
因为它不能够获得高查准率和召回率
And in particular, if a classifier
具体地说 如果一个分类模型
is getting high precision and high
拥有高查准率和召回率
recall, then we are
那么
actually confident that the algorithm
我们可以确信地说
has to be doing well, even
这个算法表现很好
if we have very skewed classes.
即便我们拥有很偏斜的类
So for the problem of skewed classes precision
因此对于偏斜类的问题
recall gives us more
查准率和召回率
direct insight into how
给予了我们更好的方法
the learning algorithm is doing
来检测学习算法表现如何
and this is often a much
这是一种
better way to evaluate our learning algorithms,
更好地评估学习算法的标准
than looking at classification error
当出现偏斜类时
or classification accuracy, when the classes are very skewed.
比仅仅只用分类误差或者分类精度好